<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title>kwaamfan's diary</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/"/>
  <link rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/atom.xml"/>
  <updated>2025-08-01T21:15:59-05:00</updated>
  <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/"/>
  <author>
    <name>kwaamfan</name>
  </author>
  <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/atom.xml</id>
  
  <entry>
    <title>friday, august 01 2025</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#16"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#16</id>
    <updated>2025-08-01T21:15:59-05:00</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>#languagelearning #played #japanese</p>
<p>have any other language learners noticed just how much ai has infiltrated language learning spaces… i feel like i'm probably beating a dead horse here bc damn near everybody in this neighborhood of the internet doesn't agree with genAI, but i've gotten so used to others sharing my convictions that every time i wander outside this bubble i'm always shocked at how much some people use it. and not just use it — <em>trust</em>  it! and not just for asking it to translate an idiom or slang not found in dictionaries here and there. i've seen people unironically suggesting others use chatgpt and other llms to:</p>
<ul>
<li>generate an entire anki deck</li>  
<li>generate short stories to read</li>
<li>have written or spoken practice conversations</li>
<li>translate and break down entire passages (before attempting to read it themselves and only asking for help on parts they don't understand)</li>
<li>generate example sentences for a target word or phrase that they found in their immersion or in the wild to add to their anki deck (instead of just… adding the original native sentence they found the word in……)</li>
</ul>  
<p>and the damn apps… i swear every other day i see someone advertising their new language learning app that's basically just chatgpt/claude/gemini etc w a custom prompt. now i'm not a software dev so i may be misunderstanding something but… what's the point.</p>
<p>really, what's the point of using llms so extensively to learn a language. it all just seems so inefficient. like after spending 15 minutes setting up yomitan or goldendict i can look up a word or phrase in multiple different dictionaries before chatgpt even loads, then if i so choose add them to my anki deck with the original context and native audio in the time it would take to prompt chatgpt for a definition. on top of that llms love making shit up so u still need to fact check it, by checking a dictionary, asking a native speaker, etc. and it's like at that point why go through the bother of generating cards in the first place? but still i see people swear up and down that the text llms produce are correct and error free. well i'm happy ur so confident in ur own ability to assess bullshit in ur target language (not that they actually can), but the beginners u keep suggesting ur methods to aren't going to know how to. and even when it is technically correct, when i've tested llms in thai to see where these people are coming from, it just fails to produce the idiomatic, slang-filled, sometimes messy but still authentic speech.</p>
<p>and that's really my biggest issue with all this. i always thought the whole reason to learn a new language was to understand people. humans. who make art and write stories and fight and cry and laugh together. to connect to people who may be from a different culture but who still understand our shared humanity. the joy of learning a language is gaining access to the thoughts and feelings of a whole new group of people u couldn't before, to hear their stories… why waste what precious time we have on this earth reading the words of a mere facsimile? what's the point of learning a language if most of ur time with it is a version processed by a machine and not the version of it that lives and breathes in this world? i think these people are going to be in for a rude awakening call when they try to interact with their target language outside of the english-ified slop their favorite llm feeds them and the pleasantries exchanged with the waitress at their local cafe. if these people want to hinder their own ability to understand the authentic speech of their target language in the long run then so be it, but it kills me to think that a beginner might follow their advice or download an app that's just ai in disguise without really thinking about the implications of it.</p>
<p>rant aside… in other news i started my first otome game in japanese, <b>ayakashi gohan</b>. i've played a couple other, shorter visual novels in japanese but this is the first otome game and first what i would personally consider "full length" (30-40+ hrs native speed) VN. i was gonna wait to post my thoughts on it until after i finished but i had the biggest jump scare playing this game that i just HAD to post about: kuroda takaya voices one of the route antagonists.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20250801ayakashigohan1.jpg" />
    <figcaption>
        <audio>
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/7hlrqa.ogg" type="audio/ogg" />
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/ur5tdf.mp3" type="audio/mp3" />
        </audio><br />
        ……くどい。俺はもう決めた。あの娘以外は考えられん<br/>
        Enough. I've already made up my mind. I can't think of anything else but her.
    </figcaption>
</figure> 
<p>y'all… when i tell you i DIED! the inhuman sound i made 😭 i knew he's done some BL work but i didn't know he worked on otomes before too. i checked vndb but unfortunately i didn't see any otomes where he voices a love interest :( still added the other otomes where he voices a minor character to my list of VNs i'd like to play one day lol. not only does he voice an antagonist in this game, he plays a tengu named guren who historically has had the right to wed a human woman from the local village. so the plot of yomi's (the actual LI) route is that guren wants to make the protagonist, rin, his wife, and keeps coming onto her despite her repeatedly telling him to get lost, and the challenge it brings to her already fraught relationship with her protector yomi. which means the route was filled with absolutely amazing lines like:</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20250801ayakashigohan2.jpg" />
    <figcaption>
        <audio>
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/hi0xhd.ogg" type="audio/ogg" />
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/1r13l8.mp3" type="audio/mp3" />
        </audio><br />
        抵抗は止めて、俺に身を委ねろ……。優しく可愛がってやるぞ<br />
        Stop resisting, and give yourself to me…. I'll treat you gently.
    </figcaption>
</figure> 
<p>when i say this had me utterly gagged… i would never survive an otome game bc i would walk straight into a bad ending if the villian sounded like kiryu kazuma. like i literally spent the whole route being like yeah rin what's the hold up, forget yomi and let's go already! 😅 i'm not usually a kiryu simp (daigo has my heart, sorry king) but kuroda's work in this route even had me like 😳 the rest of this post are my favorite lines of his along with my rough translations (may not be the best but i promise they weren't written by ai 💖), in case there are any other yakuza fans out there who might want these recordings for… reasons… or just to get a kick out of it.</p>
<figure>
    <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20250801ayakashigohan3.jpg" />
    <figcaption>
        <audio>
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/srx35z.ogg" type="audio/ogg" />
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/w0gnka.mp3" type="audio/mp3" />
        </audio><br />
        ほう……思ったより威勢がいい女だ。ますます好みだぞ<br />
        Ho… you're a more lively woman than I imagined. I like you even more. 
    </figcaption>
</figure>   
<figure>
    <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20250801ayakashigohan4.jpg" />
    <figcaption>
        <audio>
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/m045br.ogg" type="audio/ogg" />
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/whrq5z.mp3" type="audio/mp3" />
        </audio><br />
        待っていろ。妻にして欲しいと、お前の方から縋らせてやる<br />
        Just wait. I'll have you begging to be my wife. 
    </figcaption>
</figure>
<figure>
    <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20250801ayakashigohan5.jpg" />
    <figcaption>
        <audio>
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/qvbhe4.ogg" type="audio/ogg" />
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/84a62q.mp3" type="audio/mp3" />
        </audio><br />
        久し振りだな！俺が恋しくなって自ら会いに来たか？<br />
        It's been awhile! Have you finally fallen in love and come to see me? 
    </figcaption>
</figure>
<figure>
    <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20250801ayakashigohan6.jpg" />
    <figcaption>
        <audio>
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/zwheta.ogg" type="audio/ogg" />
          <source src="https://files.catbox.moe/cirflu.mp3" type="audio/mp3" />
        </audio><br />
        ……お前のそういう目は、本当にそそる。以前は拒まれもしたが、今のお前は俺のもの <br />
        That look on your face is so alluring. You used to reject me, but now you're mine. 
    </figcaption>
</figure>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>friday, july 26 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#14"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#14</id>
    <updated>2024-07-27T01:12:18Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
#plants #played
<p>the mitsuba my friend gave me finally grew enough for me to try it! a couple weeks ago a rabbit ate most of the shoots (despite being in a 3ft tall planter -_-) so i was worried but it seemed to bounce back alright. it's more bitter than i expected, but it tastes pretty good in miso soup. apparently it gets more bitter when grown in full sun compared to part shade… probably should've checked that before putting it somewhere that gets like eight hours of direct sunlight ^^;</p>
<p style="text-align:center;"><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726mitsuba.jpg" alt="a bowl of miso soup with a block of tofu, topped with japanese wild parsley." /></p>
<p>i also recently beat <strong>shin megami tensei: devil summoner raidou kuzunoha</strong>. i've read that a lot of people don't like this game (or at least the combat system) but i thought it was pretty fun. i loved that demons could be controlled directly and interact with npcs and the environment, it definitely gave the world some more charm and party formation some much needed depth. i emulated this game with <a href="https://gbatemp.net/threads/smt-devil-summoner-raidou-kuzunoha-vs-the-soulless-army-hd-textures.626763/">this hd texture pack</a> and it looks really nice. i haven't started the second game yet but i hope i have some time to this weekend. here are some of my favorite screenshots:</p>
<p style="clear:both;display: flex;justify-content: center;align-items: center; flex-flow: column wrap;"><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726moon.jpg" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726suction.jpg" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726narumi1.jpg" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726narumi2.jpg" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726narumi3.jpg" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726joke1.jpg" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726joke2.jpg" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240726joke3.jpg" /></p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>friday, june 21 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#13"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#13</id>
    <updated>2024-06-22T03:46:38Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p style="clear:both;display: flex;justify-content: center;align-items: center; flex-flow: row wrap;">
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240621macbooks.webp" style="max-width:100%;" alt="two laptops open on a desk. the left is a 13 inch macbook air and the right is a 15 inch macbook pro." />
</p>
<p>#tech</p>
<p>my mom bought a new laptop recently and gave me her old ones. they've been slow af and prone to crashes for years so she's been using her phone to watch youtube (so much that it's caused screen burn in -_-). i installed new operating systems on both of them and they seem to function better now (ubuntu server on the 2010 macbook pro and archcraft on the 2012 macbook air). i don't really have much of a use for them but it was fun trying to get them running again. i might mess around with them in the future... they both have surprisingly nice screens for decade old laptops and i feel kinda bad for turning the pro into a server ^^;</p>
<p>i'm not much of an apple fan; my current phone is an iphone xr and the only apple product i've ever bought new. throughout high school and most of college i had this one friend who would tease me, my brother, and another friend of ours for being the only people in our friend group who used android, therefore messing up imessage group chats. now that the three of us are on iphones.... honestly he had a point, imessage is really convenient when literally all your friends also have iphones. the battery on my phone is still good despite being almost five years old so i hope i can still get a couple years out of it before needing to replace it. probably with a used iphone... these days i really only use my phone to call, text, and listen to audiobooks so i don't see the benefits of buying new, and while i really dislike how much less access to FOSS software and easy control over my files the iphone has, ultimately a phone is a tool to communicate and currently an iphone provides me the least amount of friction to keeping in touch with my friends.</p>
<p style="clear:both;display: flex;justify-content: center;align-items: center; flex-flow: row wrap;">
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240621com.webp" style="max-width:100%;" alt="a 17 inch 2007 macbook pro open on a desk." />
</p>
<p>my current daily driver laptop is a thinkpad p52, but when i was in high school i had a couple different apple laptops. i still have the one above, a 17" 2007 macbook pro. about six months ago i ripped out the 1tb hard drive i had left languishing in there for nearly 10 years and put it in my current laptop's 2.5" drive bay when i started messing with dualbooting linux and needed more space on my ssds, so this laptop doesn't turn on anymore. i actually had another laptop that was a similar model that i harvested parts from to fix up the one pictured, including replacing the screen. when i was in high school my mom loved browsing craiglist to try to find good deals on used tech (especially macbooks... i still don't understand why she insists on paying a premium for apple computers when all she does is watch youtube), except she doesn't actually understand anything about technology so i was always the one who had to fix things and get them in working order. i guess it was good to learn how to do basic computer upgrades and repair, and even now i still use craiglist to buy used tech instead of buying new (i scored my current laptop for only $200!), but i could've done without the being forced on my mother's whim to spend the occasional evening setting up meetings with strangers who sometimes live an hour away just to come back and have to spend hours googling how to fix some random thing i didn't notice when inspecting it -_- the laptop i remember most fondly though that i don't have anymore was an apple ibook g3. it's THE quintessential frutiger aero piece of tech and every day i rue the fact that tech doesn't look like this anymore. the case on the macbook air i have now is translucent and the same shade of teal as the ibook i use to have (like the ad pictured below), so i guess it can be my old ibook's spiritual successor. honestly why does everything only come in like matte black or brushed aluminum these days... i was particularly fond of the charger, which is like a yo-yo since you wrap the wire around a disk.</p>
<p style="clear:both;display: flex;justify-content: center;align-items: center; flex-flow: row wrap;">
  <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240621ibook.jpg" alt="an ad for the apple ibook 3. a picture on the left shows the laptop closed with a hand holding it by a built-in handle in the hinge. a picture on the right shows the laptop open. the ad says 'Is it possible to fall in love with a computer? Oh yes. Introducing iBook. Think different.'" style="max-width: 100%;" />
  <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240621charger.webp" alt="a picture of a charger used for the apple ibook. the power supply is circular and features the apple logo in the middle." style="max-width: 100%;" />
</p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>saturday, june 15 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#12"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#12</id>
    <updated>2024-06-15T20:47:57Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
#watched #read #played #japanese
<p>last night i finally finished my rewatch/reread of the <b>cardcaptor sakura</b> franchise. i was on netflix last month when i saw that the original anime was leaving at the end of the month, and it had been a decade or so since i last watched it, so i figured i was due for a rewatch. i ended up watching it in japanese and thought it was pretty easy for the most part. i also played the playstation 1 game <b>animetic story game 1: cardcaptor sakura</b>, which loosely covers the first season of the anime. it doesn't really feel right to say i played it since there's like five minigames in the whole game, the rest is just watching scenes, but the sprite work is SO cute and the whole game only took me like 3 hours to finish so i can't really complain. i tried to rip the sprites using jpsxdec since i want to turn some into gifs for my <a href="/main/index.html?z=/main/pixels">toybox page</a> but was unsuccessful. i might mess around with using frame advancing and screenshots to manually cut and gif some sprites in the future though.</p>
<p style="clear:both;display: flex;justify-content: center;align-items: center; flex-flow: row wrap;">
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615animetic1.webp" alt="a screenshot of the game Animetic Story Game 1: Cardcaptor Sakura. Sakura, Tomoyo, and Kero are standing in the middle of King Penguin Park with small plushies surrounding them. A text box on the bottom shows Sakura saying 'Geez...!!'" style="max-width: 100%;image-rendering: pixelated;" />
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615animetic2.webp" alt="a screenshot of the game Animetic Story Game 1: Cardcaptor Sakura. A headshot of Sakura is in the middle, with large cross, square, triangle, and circle buttons of a playstation controller surround her." style="max-width: 100%;image-rendering: pixelated;" />
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615animetic3.webp" alt="a screenshot of Animetic Story Game 1: Cardcaptor Sakura. Syaoran and Sakura are on a rocky beach in front of a cave. Sakura is smiling and Syaoran is blushing and pointing at Sakura. A text box on the bottom shows Syaoran saying 'L-listen, I wasn't looking at you...!'" style="max-width: 100%;image-rendering: pixelated;" />
</p>
<p>i also read and watched the sequel <b>cardcaptor sakura: clear card</b>. even though i loved ccs as a kid i never read the sequel, probably because i was in college when the series started and wasn't into animanga at the time. luckily though the manga is finished now and i was able to binge read the whole thing ^^ i didn't really have high hopes since i don't usually care for series reboots, but i enjoyed it a lot more than i thought i would. i liked that sakura was better able to take charge of situations and leap into action, and syaoran got some moments to show off too. tomoyo and kero were just as adorable as always of course. while i think the main new character, akiho, was a little underutilized and i would've liked her more if she had a personality that wasn't the same as sakura's (i also could've used more touya and yukito tbh), i think the main mystery of <i>clear card</i> was more interesting than the original series and i like how it expanded upon some of the lore (especially around sakura's parents). i read that last year CLAMP announced a sequel to the first season after 5 years but i couldn't find any follow up. the anime had some major changes from the manga that i'm not sure how they're going to deal with in the sequel, but tbh i know i'll be happy as long as i get to see sakura and syaoran animated together again (i may have teared up when they flew together towards the end of the first season...). here are some of my favorite panels (spoiler warning):</p>
<p style="clear:both;display: flex;justify-content: center;align-items: center; flex-flow: row wrap;">
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615clearcard2.webp" alt="a manga cap of Tomoyo and Sakura from the manga Cardcaptor Sakura Clear Card. Sakura looks surprised and Tomoyo has a gentle smile on her face." />
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615clearcard4.webp" alt="a manga cap of Sakura from the manga Cardcaptor Sakura Clear Card. Sakura is wielding two swords and is leaping towards the viewer." />
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615clearcard1.webp" alt="a manga cap of Kero and Spinel from the manga Cardcaptor Sakura Clear Card. Kero says 'Looks like we got some gaming to do!' and Spinel says 'You never change, do you, old friend?!'" />
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615clearcard5.webp" alt="a manga cap of Syaoran from the manga Cardcaptor Sakura Clear Card. He is wielding a sword and has white wings." />
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615clearcard6.webp" alt="a manga cap of Kero and Spinel from the manga Cardcaptor Sakura Clear Card. Kero is yelling 'A date!! Spit it out, will ya?!' while Spinel is resting his head on one of his paws." />
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240615clearcard3.webp" alt="a manga cap of Kero, Spinel, and Touyo from the manga Cardcaptor Sakura Clear Card. Kero and Spinel are both shocked while Touyo looks expressionless. Kero yells 'When did you learn to stop time?!' and Touya says 'Oh, uh... I dunno.'" /></p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>tuesday, june 11 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#11"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#11</id>
    <updated>2024-06-11T23:48:17Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>the mitsuba seeds my friend gave to me finally sprouted! some of my other #plants are doing well too.</p>
      <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240611flowers.jpg" alt="three planters of flowers. on the left are snapdragons, in the middle are ageratums, and on the right are violets"/>
      <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240611mitsuba.jpg" alt="a close up of a planter with a dozen sprouts of japanese wild parsley"/>
      <img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240611roses.jpg" alt="a large bush of red roses in bloom."/>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>saturday, june 01 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#10"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#10</id>
    <updated>2024-06-02T02:24:26Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
<p>it's been awhile since i last wrote about what i've #read recently. i've read more non-fiction books than i normally do. i never really know how to talk about non-fiction i've read since i don't consider myself an expert on anything, so i don't have the confidence say if a book's contents is true or bullshit or whatever. especially since i like to read stuff i don't know anything about and thus don't have anything to compare it to, i often don't have any deep insight other than "this was really interesting!" but i guess that just because something doesn't move me to write an entire essay in response to it doesn't mean it's not worth sharing with others. i know i've read lots of interesting books and essays just by coming across a mention of them in various blog posts (all the books i'm about to mention are political in nature though so if you don't want to read about that feel free to skip this blog post)</p>
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240601elitecapture.jpg" alt="a cover of the book elite capture by olúfẹ́mi o. táíwò" style="float: right; padding-left: 1em;" />
<p>the first book is <b>elite capture</b> by <i>olúfẹ́mi o. táíwò</i>. he states that identity politics has strayed from its roots and has been weaponized to divide groups, even though it was originally envisioned to help build coalitions that could work together to tackle shared issues. he then argues that this didn't occur because of an issue with identity politics itself, but rather because identity politics has suffered from <i>elite capture</i>, or that political and and economic elites have co-opted it to serve their own interests. for awhile now i've been disillusioned with identity politics and standpoint theory in general, since i feel like so many people (especially online) just use such theories as an excuse to dismiss a work for not being "intersectional enough" instead of trying to engage with an idea on its own terms, or bully people who don't post about x issue affecting y group on their social media regardless of their actions irl or their focus on activism in another area; i think it's prevented many so-called leftists from building solidarity and class consciousness. even after reading this book i still feel this way, and i still think it's not just elites but average people who have fractured the left using identity politics. yet i did learn a lot about how elite capture as a process works, and the book did challenge my ideas about how it could still be used for constructive coalition building.</p>
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240601therighteousmind.jpg" alt="a cover of the book righteous mind: why good people are divided by politics and religion by jonathan haidt" style="float: left;padding-right: 1em;" />
<p>the next book is the <b>righteous mind: why good people are divided by politics and religion</b> by <i>jonathan haidt</i>. he explores how humans evolved our moral intuitions and argues that this intuition comes before our reasoning and justifications for it. he goes on to expound upon his six foundations of morality theory and how they build moral matrices, which in turn works to bind groups together and promote behavior among individuals that benefit group interests, even at the cost of self-interest. i think his theory on how morality works is interesting a definitely aligns with my own experience talking to others about right and wrong and our reactions to ideas that go against our beliefs. i find the final sections where he applies his moral foundations theory to american political analysis a little lackluster though. i guess from the title of the book i thought it was going to be a bigger focus and more in depth than it ended up being, and while i think the earlier sections do a good job at backing up his claims with studies, i think the later sections rely a little too much on constructing narratives to illustrate his point. he also sort of skirts around the issue of how large groups like nations can effectively balance the competing moral matrices of its subgroups when they are often incompatible. i agree with his argument that groups being exclusionary and having different ideals isn't a bad thing, but most of his examples are too small and local to feel compelling. it's like he's afraid of discussing how exactly we're meant to embrace pluralism in the real world when part of another group's ideology oppresses members of our own group. it reminds me of another book i read earlier this year, <b>prey</b> by <i>ayaan hirsi ali</i>, which argues that unchecked immigration from muslim majority countries into the eu has lead to a spike in sexual violence towards women. she explains how islamic culture shapes these men's view on women, and that moving outside of the restrictions of islamic communities can cause some to commit violence against women. she contends that the left's unwillingness to criticize these viewpoints is due to political correctness, that this violence is causing some voters to turn towards the right, and that european nations need to promote more assimilation when accepting refuges in order to protect women's rights. while haidt argues in <i>the righteous mind</i> that liberals tend to care so much about the care/harm and liberty/oppression foundation that it inhibits their ability to understand and accept other moralities, i think that those on the left do accept pluralism in some cases—just not white christian morality—even at the expense of the well-being of members in their own group (in this case, women). i realize that haidt's book is mainly meant to be descriptive of how differing morality systems are formed and their evolutionary benefit instead of prescriptive of what systems are right or not, but to basically end the book with saying "let's all talk to each other in good faith 💖" just felt shallow. it's also painfully obvious to me that this book was published in 2012. i read <b>antisocial</b> by <i>andrew marantz</i> earlier this year as well which discusses the rise of the american alt-right and how social media has made it easier to become radicalized into extremist ideology, and i would love to see how haidt would apply his morality theory to more niche political groups such as the alt-right as it's clear that when he discusses american conservatives he's referring to the traditional christian kind and not necessarily the reactionary libertarian trolls marantz discusses in his book.</p>
<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240601thecreationofpatriarchy.jpg" alt="a cover of the book the creation of patriarchy by gerda lerner" style="float: right;padding-left: 1em;" />
<p>the last book i wanted to mention is <b>the creation of patriarchy</b> by <i>gerda lerner</i>. she traces how patriarchy as a way of structuring society developed in western civilization starting from ancient mesopotamia, and argues that while biological differences exist between men and women, gendered relationships are something that evolved over time. honestly it was way more in depth about discussing the archaeological evidence for her theories than i was anticipating, and considering the fact that i almost never read about ancient history and am uneducated on the topics she was writing about it was tough at times for me to digest everything. i can't really speak authoritatively on the accuracy of her arguments since i know fuck all about ancient history, but i think the tone with which she writes is engaging and she writes clearly enough that i could more or less follow her main points even when they were hard for me to believe (her speculation that man learned how to subjugate and enslave other groups by first subjugating women stands out to me as one). the prose also didn't make the book feel as though it were published in 1986, it never seemed dry or overly academic. i generally find history books boring i found myself compelled to keep picking this one up.</p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>sunday, may 19 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#9"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#9</id>
    <updated>2024-05-20T03:59:16Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
      <p>my friends just got back from japan! this is what they brought back for me. now i've gotten my fair share of grow-in-a-cup sets that are always too small to germinate all the seeds they supply but this is by far the most egregious lmao. there's gotta be more than 20 seeds in this bag. did the manufacturer expect me to germinate each seed individually or something? the cup is cute and i've never eaten the plant, japanese wild parsley, before so i'm quite excited to try it out... but i'll definitely be sowing it in a real planter tomorrow. i was also quite surprised by how much of the packaging and instructions i could read. last week i got some japanese stationary (a pilot kakuno fountain pen and a kokuyo campus notebook and paper) whose instructions i could read a fair bit too. maybe i have actually learned something in the last eight months i've been studying japanese?!</p>
			<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240519mitsuba.jpg" />
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Saturday, May 11 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#8"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#8</id>
    <updated>2024-05-11T19:56:59Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
			<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240511flowers.jpg" style="float:right;max-width: 350px;" alt="two planters. one has white and pink snapdragons and the other has light blue and purple violets." />
      <p>this past thursday was the first day of the farmer's market that i usually go to. the first couple weeks it's usually just starter herbs and flowers, plus some hanging baskets of flowers. this year in addition to the usual basil, thyme, and other herbs i like to grow, i bought some snapdragons and violets to put in planters to spruce up my front door steps a bit. i really enjoy this part of spring, past the last chance of snow and freezing temps where i can finally get a bit of gardening done before the heat of summer comes, even though i have to suffer through my seasonal allergies.</p>
      <p>i also cleaned up some files on my pc since my storage is running a bit low. here's some gaming screenshots that i particularly liked but never posted anywhere.</p>
      <p style="clear:both;display: flex;justify-content: center;align-items: center; flex-flow: column wrap;"><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240511days.jpg" alt="a photo of the Nintendo DS game Kingdom Hearts 358/2 Days. Larxene says to Roxas 'What do you want? I'm busy. Go hit your head against the glass or something.'" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240511trails.jpg" alt="a screenshot of the game Trails in the Sky the 3rd. Ries Argent says to Kevin Graham 'You've been a loser since the day I met you. I don't expect that to change any time soon.'" /><img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240511gaiden.jpg" alt="a screenshot of the game Like a Dragon Gaiden: The Man Who Erased His Name. the protagonist Kiryu Kazuma is wearing aviator sunglasses, gold hoop earrings, black nail polish, a gold chain necklace, and a replica of Majima Goro's snakeskin jacket. he says 'You'll see me dead before you ever see me on my knees.'" /></p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Monday, May 06 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#7"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#7</id>
    <updated>2024-05-07T00:24:59Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
      &lt;figure style=&quot;float:right;max-width: 350px;margin-left: 1em;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240506peach.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;pink flowers on a peach tree&quot; /&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;the peach tree in my backyard bloomed like two weeks ago but they're still hanging on... proud of her&lt;/figcaption&gt;
      &lt;/figure&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;i added a new &lt;a href=&quot;https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/places/index.html&quot;&gt;page&lt;/a&gt; on my site last week for my favorite video game locations. i've had this idea for awhile now, and i knew i wanted animated backgrounds, but i didn't know how to best implement them. after fiddling with turning my recordings into gif, webp, and mp4 files i learned about the avif format and omg the file size... it's like a tenth of the size of the gif versions i made and the quality is way better too. i was able to make the gif on my languages page 5mb (it was originally... 50mb....... 🙈) and the haruka gif on my resources site homepage only 552 kb! makes me wonder what the hell i was doing spending all that time on tumblr making gifsets while fighting for my life to make each gif less than 10mb 😭 i still have more places i want to add, but i need to find more free cam/no hud mods for some games.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;i also overhauled my &lt;a href=&quot;https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/resources/index.html&quot;&gt;resources site&lt;/a&gt; to be generated with &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.11ty.dev/&quot;&gt;11ty&lt;/a&gt;. it's now completely navigable without javascript enabled, even on mobile 🥳 i'm gonna keep tweaking my personal site to be functional without javascript. i saw some examples of pure css sidebar toggle on codepen that i want to try to implement. i doubt anyone who might view this site on mobile would also not have javascript enabled (tbh it's hard to think that anyone views this site at all), but i think it's a fun challenge. i feel like i learn more about what's possible with just html and css, and it gives me new ideas for my site.&lt;/p&gt;
    </content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tuesday, April 30 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#6"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#6</id>
    <updated>2024-05-01T01:55:41Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
		&lt;figure style=&quot;float:right;max-width: 350px;margin-left: 1em;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/microblog/images/20240430tulips.avif&quot; alt=&quot;red and yellow tulips starting to bloom&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;the flowers in my garden are starting to bloom&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i made a bunch of changes to the site this past week, mainly stuff behind the scenes. most notably i added an &lt;a href=&quot;/microblog/atom.xml&quot;&gt;atom feed&lt;/a&gt; for my microblog. i checked it with the browser extension &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://nodetics.com/feedbro/&quot;&gt;feedbro&lt;/a&gt; and it looks okay i think. i also made one for updates to the rest of my site, which you can access &lt;a href=&quot;/atom.xml&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. i enabled rss autodiscovery on the main pages as well to make adding it to your rss reader a bit easier. in addition to moving to neocities, as part of my ongoing effort to curb my social media use i'm also trying to read more blogs, essays, and other long-form written media by subscribing to substacks and rss feeds, and i figured i may as well make it possible for others to do the same with my site. (as a side note - i recently discovered the read it later app &lt;a href=&quot;https://omnivore.app/&quot;&gt;omnivore&lt;/a&gt; and it's been really helpful in actually finishing reading articles i find interesting. i know other read it later apps have existed for a long time, idk why i've been sleeping on them until now.) i restructured a bunch of stuff in the code too, mostly switching some &lt;code&gt;div&lt;/code&gt;s for semantic tags and converting all jquery to vanilla javascript, so if something looks broken try hard refreshing (ctrl+f5). turns out theres so much more to web development than the random bits i hacked together from tutorials and stack overflow answers making tumblr themes in 2015... i'm not sure if my site is actually any more accessible or loads faster and i still need to test things with an actual screen reader, but i think my code is easier to read at least.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure style=&quot;float:left;max-width: 500px;margin-right: 1em;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/microblog/images/20240430leifan.avif&quot; alt=&quot;fei and lan from the video game piofiore. lan says 'We do know a little bit about drugs. Isn't that neat?! That's 'cause we're the Lao-Shu!'&quot;&gt;
    &lt;figcaption&gt;honestly these 15 year olds carried yang's route&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i think i've had some sort of ear infection for the last couple days. i was gonna go to the doctor today if i wasn't feeling any better when i woke up, but it doesn't hurt anymore so i didn't end up going. i don't know what's up with my body this past year, i usually only get sick once or twice a year but i got sick like three times this winter alone -_- i took advantage of all the time i spent this weekend lying on my side to catch up on some manga (i may or may not have been like 6 months behind on chainsaw man 🙈).&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;figure style=&quot;float:right;max-width: 500px;margin-left: 1em;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/microblog/images/20240430danteyang.avif&quot; alt=&quot;dante and yang from the video game piofiore. yang says 'Acting to protect someone only increases the probability of death.'&quot;&gt;
        &lt;figcaption&gt;sorry for talking shit about u dante u did look pretty hot here&lt;/figcaption&gt;
    &lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i also #played some &lt;b&gt;piofiore&lt;/b&gt; and managed to finish yang's and dante's routes. now yang's route definitely lived up to its notoriety in the otome community but i found his best ending a little underwhelming. i usually do bad and good endings before the best ending and i found those really thrilling (i was even a little moved at the good ending ngl... may have even shed a tear or two) but the best ending... idk. i didn't dislike it but it wasn't as fun as his other endings or nicola's best ending. i found dante a little boring too. i think he kinda got shafted by having to carry the plot of the game on his route lol. i was grateful to finally learn about the key maiden stuff but honestly i spent the first half wishing i could've romanced leo instead. i'm halfway done with this game now and am looking forward to gilbert's route especially. orlock isn't really the type of LI i usually like but i'm also really intrigued by his role in the plot especially after seeing... yang's? best ending epilogue. why tf is he blonde....&lt;/p&gt;
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sunday, April 21 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#5"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#5</id>
    <updated>2024-04-21T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="html">
		&lt;p&gt;recently i wrote a &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://userstyles.world/style/15915/neocities-no-followers-modified&quot;&gt;stylesheet&lt;/a&gt; for the browser extension &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://addons.mozilla.org/en-US/firefox/addon/styl-us/&quot;&gt;stylus&lt;/a&gt; to hide the stats underneath the header on neocities profiles, as well as the follower/following list in the sidebar. after the implosion of federiefederi i've been reflecting a little on why i've been moving away from #socialmedia and what i want to get out of neocities. i've been trying to break out of the mindset i tend to have on other sites of obsessively checking my activity, how many likes my posts get, who does or doesn't follow me, who's popular and who isn't, etc that's been instilled in me from spending more than half my life online. in general i like the neocities activity feed and seeing people's new pages and updates, and i don't find that that affects my brain negatively, but i feel like the visible follower and view count does. so i removed it. i know it doesn't affect other people's ability to see how many people follow me or who i follow but that doesn't bother me.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure style=&quot;float: right;max-width: 100%;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;div style=&quot;display: flex; flex-direction: row; margin-left: 1em; &quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/microblog/images/20240421xstitch.avif&quot; alt=&quot;a partially finished cross stitch. a shiny umbreon from the video game series pokemon is lying down.&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 350px;width: auto;max-width: 50%;object-fit: cover;&quot;&gt;
        &lt;img src=&quot;/microblog/images/20240421eeveelution.avif&quot; alt=&quot;a cross stitch pattern of 8 different evolutions of eevees from the video game series pokemon lounging on a cat tower. they are all shiny variants.&quot; style=&quot;max-height: 350px;width: auto;max-width: 50%;object-fit: cover;flex-shrink: 0;&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;
    &lt;figcaption style=&quot;clear: both;&quot;&gt;11.66% done vs original. &lt;a target=&quot;_blank&quot; href=&quot;https://www.etsy.com/listing/1481310191/eeveelutions-cafe-shiny-edition-pattern&quot;&gt;pattern link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;i #cross-stitched a little this weekend too. according to pattern keeper i'm now over 10% done with this project 🥳 i bought this pattern last july so at this rate i think i'll be done in 7 years? i randomly saw it on etsy one day and thought it was SO cute i just bought it - even though i'm not a pokemon fan lmao. luckily one of my besties is a big pokemon fan so i can give it to him... if i ever finish it. maybe i should work a liiiiittle harder and try to finish it before he graduates dental school... maybe.&lt;/p&gt;
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sunday, April 14 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#4"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#4</id>
    <updated>2024-04-14T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
			<figure style="max-width: 200px;float:right">
			<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240413bag.avif" alt="a blue and white crocheted bag" />
			<figcaption>i promise this is a bag and not just a triangle... <a target="_blank" href="https://www.1dogwoof.com/weekend-wanderer-mesh-bento-bag-crochet-pattern/">pattern link</a></figcaption>
			</figure>
			<p>i've been sick the last couple of days, but i'm starting to feel better. i #crocheted this bag with some yarn i found at a thrift store a year ago. i haven't done any fiber arts for like two months since all the windows in my house were replaced recently, so a bunch of stuff had to be packed away. now that everything's been put back i've been able to go through my fiber arts WIPs and tbh i didn't feel like doing any of them lol. i think that since it was all cold weather stuff and now that it's >70°F/20°C i just don't have the motivation to finish them right now and just wanted a quick and easy project to get back into the swing of things.</p>
			<p>while crocheting i also #read two books by <em>keigo higashino</em>, <a target="_blank" href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/582f3ad9-7138-4297-9e89-e4340573fabc">a death in tokyo</a> and <a target="_blank" href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/1233629b-9d0d-4c3e-afe9-a60101400de2">the final curtain</a>. i think that makes four or five books i've read by him in the past year. i always thought of myself as a fantasy girlie but idk, i've been getting really into japanese murder mysteries this year. i really like how higashino's books aren't really just about the murder mystery but more about the people surrounding the victim, the problems in society and our relationships that can drive people to murder, and how murder and death affect people and how we treat people who have recently experienced loss. i also like how in these two books we see more of kaga as a person, and i'm sad that there aren't any more books featuring detective kaga translated into english. guess that means i just have to work harder at studying japanese 😔</p>
			<figure style="max-width: 300px;float:left">
				<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240414zhao.avif" alt="on the left is an image of the character yang from the video game piofiore. on the right is an image of the character tianyou zhao from the video game yakuza: like a dragon" />
				<figcaption>if someone told me these two were voiced by the same guy i would've picked up piofiore ages ago</figcaption>
			</figure>
			<p>i also #played <b>piofiore</b> for a little bit... i've been in a bit of an otome slump since trying out and dropping virche evermore in january. so far i've only played through nicola's route (idek how i got on his route lmao). as a LI he was nice but didn't really do anything to captivate me. i liked the story though and am looking forward to the other routes, especially yang's since he shares a voice actor with tianyou zhao from the yakuza series.</p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Wednesday, April 10 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#3"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#3</id>
    <updated>2024-04-10T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
			<p>i've now been on neocities for one month now! i think i've managed to get a lot done in one month. although i've spent most of that time thinking of what i want my site to look like and then coding it. i was inspired to join neocities because i just feel like i haven't been having fun on #socialmedia recently, and i thought i'd see if making my own website would be a more fulfilling use of my internet time. i've actually been trying to decrease the amount of time i spend online, which probably sounds stupid since i have to code this site from scratch, but it's actually been a really fun creative outlet. i like to think that if i spend more of my internet time on more fulfilling projects i'll spend less time on less fulfilling (but more instantly gratifying) activities like scrolling through social media.</p>
			<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/moshimoshi.avif" alt="the cover of the book moshi moshi by banana yoshimoto" style="float: right; padding: 1em 0 1em 1em; max-width: 50%;" />
			<p>this week i #read <a target="_blank" href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/cab53bbd-96fc-48db-8376-adeb83a6dadd">moshi moshi</a> by <em>banana yoshimoto</em>. the only other book of hers i've read is <a target="_blank" href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/fde5e557-e570-426e-a77c-b8c186714487">the premonition</a> which i didn't really like, although i liked the writing style. i don't know how to describe why i didn't like it other than it was just weird. usually i like that in a book but when i was reading that book i was like "wtf is wrong with these people" in a 🤨 way. like the plot... idk. vibes were off. luckily <b>moshi moshi</b> gives "wtf is wrong with these people" in a much more enjoyable way. i loved the relationship between the mother and the daughter in this book. i feel like i'm sort of going through the same thing in my life, with the whole learning about your parents as adults and humans now that they don't really need to parent you anymore and how your relationships with them change because of that. i also loved the vivid description of the main characters' life and sense of community living in shimokitazawa. maybe it's just because i live in suburban america but living in a diverse urban area and being able to walk or take a taxi to all the cool places they go in the book sounds like a dream. here's a quote i really like that i think captures central themes of the healing power of food and community when you're grieving well in a few sentences:</p>
			<blockquote><p>We'd been carrying around a sense of someone missing—someone we might be able to find if only we knew where to go, then things might become clear.</p><p>We didn't cry then and there in the bistro, but the feeling of the cells in our bodies welcoming the sudden influx of nutrients was as refreshing as crying in a speeding car with the windows rolled down, letting tears fly. Like finally sitting yourself down at your destination at the end of an exhausting journey.</p><p>Michiyo-san didn't know what we were going through, nor did she console us directly. All she did was put herself into her food and offer it to us. That was obvious in everything about the restaurant—everything there was as real and as certain as anything could be.</p><q>Moshi Moshi</q> by <cite>Banana Yoshimoto</cite></blockquote>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Sunday, April 07 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#2"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#2</id>
    <updated>2024-04-07T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
			<p>my friend who moved to boston for dental school came back for a visit this weekend. sometimes when i hang out with people that i've been friends with since childhood i get this feeling like i'm standing still in the middle of a busy intersection. now that i'm almost 26 more and more of my friends are moving cross country for jobs or grad school. this one guy i've known since elementary school and has been dating this girl from his college friend group for a couple years is even talking about getting married once they move in a month and settle into their new life (also to boston... wtf is in boston that's making all my friends move there). and it genuinely makes me happy to see my friends grow up and do things with their life! but it makes me feel like i should want to do more with myself and my #life but i just... don't. i've never been interested in marriage or kids or even dating, and even though when i was a kid i thought i wanted to go to grad school now that i'm graduated and working i just don't have that same ambition. i think it's hard for my irl friends to understand that i'm okay still living with my parents and working from home, just spending my free time on my hobbies like language learning and gaming and now building this site. actually right now living with my mom is quite useful since i can practice thai with her every day. i've met a lot of people online who have a similar life situation and attitude as myself so i don't think it's all that uncommon, but sometimes i think my friends pity me or something when it's really not like that.</p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Thursday, April 04 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#1"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#1</id>
    <updated>2024-04-04T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
			<p>this week i #read <a target="_blank" href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/ddef3591-d299-4536-bffd-84c3ed3cfdc4">age of vice</a> by <em>deepti kapoor</em> and <a target="_blank" href="https://app.thestorygraph.com/books/681ebf7e-7c19-41ad-8b07-eac511dcce8b">invisible women: data bias in a world designed for men</a> by <em>caroline criado pérez</em>. the vast majority of the time i say i read a book i really mean i listened to the audiobook. i like to listen to audiobooks when i do household chores. with the weather warming up here in minnesota, i've been doing my spring cleaning – deep cleaning the kitchen and bathrooms, cleaning and storing my winter clothes, bringing out the summer clothes, and getting ready to start gardening. this gave me plenty of time to get through these two large books in the space of a week.</p>
			<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/ageofvice.avif" alt="cover of the book Age of Vice by Deepti Kapoor" style="float: left; padding: 1em 1em 1em 0;max-width:50%;" />
			<p><em>cw: mentions of drugs, violence, car crashes, and death</em> i don't remember why i decided to read <b>age of vice</b>. to be honest like 80% of the books i read i just see on libby or hoopla, think the cover looks good or the short blurb sounds interesting, then put it on hold. so by the time i'm actually able to check it out and read it i've forgotten all about what drew me to it in the first place. it follows the story of sunny wadia, the heir to a powerful mobster family, his servant ajay, and his journalist girlfriend neda. the book starts with a car crash that kills five people in new dehli, seemingly caused by ajay. not really the story i typically reach for, since i mainly read fantasy, but i've been on a bit of a crime thriller kick the last couple of months so i'm guessing this is why i put it on hold like 3 months ago. soon we go back to ajay's childhood and spend like a third of the book going through his past, how he meets sunny and starts to work for him, and gradually come to understand the wadia family from the perspective of an outsider. i loved this part of the book – i found ajay and his journey so captivating. but when the perspective moved to neda is when the book started to lose me. a journalist getting involved with the playboy son of a violent gang family, who is being investigated by the newspaper she works at, sounds like it should be interesting, but she ends up being the most boring character in the book. i don't know how to describe her other than she feels like she was written by a man, but the author is a woman, so... it's like she has no interiority. not that any of the other characters do either but i felt like she had the most potential, just to end up being defined entirely by her relationship to a man. and the man is fucking sunny wadia. even after all the time i spent watching her become interested in and then falling in love with him, i couldn't find a single redeeming quality to him. honestly he seemed cooler when i was reading from ajay's perspective. like if it was revealed at some point that ajay was in love with sunny i would've been like "okay, i could see how he could develop those feelings given his life circumstances" but neda? girl... love yourself. by the time we switch to sunny's perspective for the last third i was basically entirely checked out at that point. really the only reason i didn't DNF was because i was still invested in ajay's downward spiral. like while ajay was dealing with the trauma of trying to reunite with the family he lost as a child and the increasing level of violence he was expected to perform as part of his duties, sunny's downward spiral was just... drinking more and doing more cocaine. groundbreaking. the final parts of the book that take place after the reader learns the truth of the car crash was just confusing to me. i think i would've had an easier time if i was reading and not listening to the audiobook, but i absolutely would've DNF'd by that point if i was actually reading it. i've also read other reviews that mention feeling lost in the last part too, so maybe it's not just a me thing. besides ajay, the only other thing i really liked about this book was the prose. i think the blunt, detached air of it was fitting for the atmosphere of the book.</p>
			<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/invisiblewomen.avif" alt="cover of the book Invisible Women by caroline criado pérez" style="float: right; padding: 1em 0em 1em 1em;max-width:50%;" />
			<p>i've had <b>invisible women</b> in my to read list for awhile now. the book discusses how women are often not considered when it comes to collecting data on basically every facet of life. the author claims that this arises from how we consider men to be the default human, with words like "man" and "mankind" being understood to include women, so people often assume that conclusions drawn from men's opinions or studies using mostly men will apply to women too; pérez goes on to show just how pervasive this mindset is and how it's actually inaccurate at best and actively harmful at worst. i think i didn't read this book earlier because i wasn't sure if i was in the mood to read about stuff i assumed i was pretty knowledgeable about already. and i was right, that i didn't learn a ton of new information from this book, but i do read a fair bit of feminist literature. since i just needed something to listen to while i cleaned, it didn't bore me though. the audiobook is read by the author and you can definitely feel her frustration at points which i personally liked, although i've read some reviews that disliked it. to me the most interesting chapters were the final ones, that discuss how women aren't included in disaster relief planning and that this leads to prioritizing rebuilding for businesses before public housing, walkability and safe transit, and mixed use areas that women are more likely to want and utilize. it's not something that i had ever thought of before, how even zoning laws and city planning are disproportionately affect women.</p>
			<img src="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/images/20240404sweater.avif" alt="lilac mock neck drop sleeve cropped cashmere sweater" style="float: left; padding: 1em 1em 1em 0;max-width:30%;" />
			<p>in addition to doing a bunch of cleaning and listening to audiobooks i also #thrifted this sweater. it's a cashmere sweater in a pretty lilac color by the brand theory. i'm not that familiar with fashion but i thought i had heard the name before, plus most of the cashmere sweaters i've thrifted have been from charter club or j crew in boring cuts. so when i saw this sweater in a bit of a trendier style and color i was a bit curious as to how much it would retail for. turns out the original price was <a target="_blank" href="https://outlet.theory.com/cropped-mock-neck-sweater-in-cashmere/L0718702.html">$325</a> 😭😭😭 it makes me feel better for spending 7 whole dollars on it despite the weird patch of pilling on the front.</p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title>Tuesday, April 02 2024</title>
    <link href="https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#0"/>
    <id>https://kwaamfan.neocities.org/microblog/#0</id>
    <updated>2024-04-02T00:00:00Z</updated>
    <content type="xhtml">
		<div xmlns="http://www.w3.org/1999/xhtml">
			<p>welcome to my microblog! i wanted a place on my website where i could write about whatever i felt like, whenever i wanted, without feeling like i need to build a dedicated page around said topic. when i was thinking about how i want to present my thoughts, i went looking at how other people keep blogs on their neocities. i like <a href="https://status.cafe/">status.cafe</a> as a sort of twitter-like alternative for short thoughts, but i wanted to be able to write longer pieces plus sort posts by tags. i also felt like a more traditional blog-like framework such as <a href="https://codeberg.org/01bbl/Zonelots">zonelots</a> would put too much pressure on me to write long posts if i only want to write a couple sentences. i guess i was looking for a more tumblr-like alternative that can balance the two but without all the <a target="_blank" href="https://webcache.googleusercontent.com/search?q=cache:https://medium.com/mental-health-and-addictions-community/the-noise-pollution-of-social-media-and-the-web-a500eccf8e0f">noise</a> that a #socialmedia platform brings. when i stumbled upon <a href="https://notabug.org/likho/microblog.py">microblog.py</a> it seemed like the perfect fit for my use case. for awhile now i've wanted to blog more about my hobbies and interests because i like looking back at my previous thoughts on what i've played, read, etc but <a target="_blank" href="https://notes.andymatuschak.org/Evergreen_notes?stackedNotes=zXDPrYcxUSZbF5M8vM5Y1U9">trying to write for an audience felt paralyzing to me</a>, and when i do end up sharing stuff online it's like i could feel my brain obsessing over views and likes and replies even when i knew i wasn't sharing stuff for engagement. yet it felt weird to write fandom related stuff in obsidian next to my personal notes about thai grammar and bayesian analysis and whatnot. like i love using obsidian to write notes about things i'm trying to learn, but i didn't really want to mix in the notes i write more like a diary entry to just rant or rave about stuff. i do sometimes write about it in physical journals, but i also like being able to search for things easily and embed digital content like screenshots. i think the appeal of having your own site to write about these kinds of things is that strangers can still read it, think about it, and interact with you if they really want to, but unlike social media platforms it's not like it'll appear on their feed or dashboard, inviting them to tell you your opinions are wrong <a target="_blank" href="https://web.archive.org/web/20210415215649/https://mikkeneko.tumblr.com/post/169325179934/how-web-20-and-especially-tumblr-is-ruining">if they feel like it intrudes upon their space</a>. i'm also just not a social person in general despite enjoying reading other people's blogs and opinions, so not feeling like i must respond to every single rando who finds my posts makes me feel more comfortable writing more openly. it'll probably be a couple days between writing this and publishing it on my website since i still have to write the css and make sure everything works, but i look forward to trying out this format of journaling.</p>
		</div>
	</content>
  </entry>
  

</feed>